ROGER MOORE

18 Old Harrow Road, St. Leonards-on-Sea | East Sussex, TN37 7EG | 07449568309 | me@rogermoore.io rogermoore.io | github.com/rmoore74

PROFILE

Final year Computer Science student at King's College London. On target for a 2:1. Recently completed a 13-month placement, working as a full-time software developer at SAP in their satellite office in Knutsford. Strong interest and focus on Big Data, having worked with technologies such as Hadoop, Spark, Scala, NoSQL databases (MongoDB), SAP HANA, read multiple books on the subject, and with plans to focus my dissertation/final year project in this area. Also have a keen interest in open-source technology, particularly technologies such as Apache Cassandra, Spark, and Hadoop, as well as the whole Node.js ecosphere. Linux user and Vim enthusiast.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Hons), Computer Science with a Year in Industry

2013 to 2017

- King's College London
 - Strong focus on theory and programming throughout. Predominantly programmed using Java, with an emphasis on writing efficient and coherent programs, implementing data structures, and design patterns. Also exposed to functional programming languages such as Haskell, and logic-based languages such as PROLOG.
- Achieved a 2:1 in both first and second year.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Development Intern, 13-month placement

2015 to 2016

- SAP UK, Knutsford
 - Working and developing with the SAP HANA platform as a part of the Scrum team in Knutsford. Using and experiencing technologies such as Maven, Selenium, Git, Gerrit, Jenkins, ReviewNinja, SAP HANA, SAPUI5, Linux, Java, SQL, Server-Side Javascript, Javascript, and C#.
 - Designed and created new reporting tool for Total Margin Management, a tool currently being implemented by ConAgra foods to help simplify their overall reporting process. Built using mainly C# for the application design (Excel addin), utilising REST APIs, using SQL, server-side JavaScript, and following a Scrum agile methodology. The back-end ran on SAP HANA. Used Hana Studio to manage Hana Database.
- Exploring and investigating Big Data and 'Internet of Things' technologies. Creating multiple proof-of-concepts (PoC) using various technologies such as Hadoop/HDFS, Apache Spark (implemented using Scala), Apache Kafka, Apache Ambari, SAP Hana Vora, SAP Smart Data Streaming, etc.
- Worked as part of a scrum team, as a developer, to help design and create main IoT PoC project. Working with technologies such as JSON Web Tokens (JWT), NodeJS, MongoDB, Hana Cloud Platform, SAP IoT: Application Services, and CloudFoundry.
- Worked on the user interface for the IoT project, creating a mobile-first front-end for our project. Used the SAPUI5 framework. Followed the MVC pattern, defining XML views, and separating logic using Javascript controllers and models. Based off of a Java Spring RESTful back-end.
- Investigated, prepared, and presented presentations for rest of the team to inform on technologies, e.g., JWT.
- Nominated twice for the SAP Instant Hero award, based on teamwork and productivity. Received £150 worth of points for each nomination.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Programming

- Experience in Java, C#, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, Hadoop, Spark, Kafka, Spring, Scala, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, XML, MVC, MVVM, REST, C++, JWT, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Git, Maven, Gerrit, Jenkins, Selenium, Visual Basic 6.0 and .NET.
- Designed and developed a Race Data application in Java, using Swing GUI, Twitter4J, and JFreeChart libraries. Created for a coursework project at King's, this application connects and pulls data from the internet, allowing the user to search freely through races. Other functionality allows users to select race candidates and add them as friends, view a graphical

- representation of the data (in the form of charts, using JFreeChart), and allows the user to connect with their Twitter account to tweet race results straight from the application (using Twitter4J).
- Created a 3D game application using C++ and the DarkGDK library. The game allows the user to walk around terrain with functional physics and collision detection. User is able to jump up and down, move about, and fall off of objects without any problems. User cannot walk through solid objects.
- Created a replica of the Enigma machine for a coursework project in 6th form. Using Visual Basic .NET, I created a functioning replica of the Enigma machine.
- Experience with distributed version control system, Git. Used in a professional environment as SAP individual coursework at university, as well as in group project coursework.

Website Development

- Experience developing web applications using Node.js. Mainly built using the MEAN stack. This is MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJS, and Node.js.
- Experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, and MySQL. Using the LAMP stack; Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP.
- Designed and created website using HTML, CSS, and jQuery for my homepage at: rogermoore.io. However, I am currently refurbishing the whole website and I am moving to a MEAN web application, which is currently live. I have decided to create a single-page application, focusing heavily on using AngularJS to handle routing and front-end functionality, etc. To keep the length of the CV down, you can view more of my work on this website.

Operating Systems

- Microsoft Certified IT Professional
- Experience in using Windows operating systems
- Experience in using Linux operating systems; Ubuntu, Fedora, CentOS, Arch Linux.
- Experience in using Mac operating systems

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Customer Service Assistant

2012 to 2013

Sainsbury's, St. Leonards-on-Sea

- Worked as a customer service assistant for my local Sainsbury's. My main job was to work in the checkout department; however I also helped out in other departments around the store, such as the self-service checkout, or trolleys whenever I had the chance or when it was required.
- Experience in communicating with customers and providing customer service, receiving Sainsbury's "gold star" feedback from customers.
- Awarded a Level 2 Diploma in Retail Skills.

IT Apprentice

February – July

2011

Zenos IT Academy, Brighton

- Learned the basics of computer hardware, software, networking, and how to provide IT support.
- Gained a Level 3 Advanced Apprenticeship in IT & Telecoms Professionals.
- Also obtained various vendor qualifications such as MCITP, MTA: Networking Fundamentals, MTA: Operating System Fundamentals, and CompTIA A+ (which has since expired).
- Awarded Level 3 Diploma in ICT Professional Competence, Level 3 Diploma for ICT Systems and Principles for IT
 Professionals, Level 2 Key Skills in Communication, Level 2 Key Skills in Application of Number, and a Level 2 Award
 in Employability and Personal Development.
- · Chosen for "Learner's Learner" in my group.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- **Programming:** I have always had a great fascination for programming and how things worked. I created my first website (a site for Pokemon tips and tricks) at the age of 7, following books that I had found laying about the house. This has naturally progressed as I have grown up and technology has improved.
- **Music:** I have a great passion for music. I have been playing the guitar since the age of 10 and have been entirely self-taught since then.